Guide to the Charles B. Johnson Confederate Supply Requisition Records, 1861-1865 MS 332
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Charles B. Johnson Confederate Supply Requisition records
1861-1865
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Johnson, Charles B.
MS 332
0.1 Linear Feet (1 folder)
Charles B. Johnson Confederate Supply Requisition records pertain to the business of the Wichita Indian Agency as well as receipts, quartermasters' store lists, payment abstracts, invoices, and records of acquisitions made by the Confederate States of America in the State of Texas.
Biographical Sketch
Charles B. Johnson of Johnson and Grimes, was a quartermaster in the Indian Territory, now known as Oklahoma and Texas. He helped to supply various Confederate military outfits with food. He was also from time to time ordered to furnish Indians with favorable relationships with the Confederate Government food and supplies.
Scope and Contents
Charles B. Johnson Confederate Supply Requisition records pertain to the business of the Wichita Indian Agency as well as receipts, quartermasters' store lists, payment abstracts, invoices, and records of acquisitions made by the Confederate States of America in the State of Texas.
Restrictions on Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored onsite at the Woodson Research Center.
Acquisition Information
Purchased for the Fondren Library by the O.W.L.S., 1932.
Index Terms
Subjects
American Civil War (United States: 1861-1865); Requisitions, Military -- Texas; Military
Document Types
corrrespondence; receipts (financial records); financial records
Places
United States; Texas
Subjects (Corporations)
United States. Office of Indian Affairs. Wichita Agency; Johnson and Grimes; Confederate States of America. Army
- Series I: 1861-1862, 22312
  - Letter from unknown to Johnson and Grimes Re: Price of Rations, Novemeber 16, 1861; 22319 (Folder 1)
  - Note from C.A. Rickel to J.J. Sturm Re: Issuance of Rations (includes two copies), February 1, 1862; 22318 (Folder 1)
  - Document signed by A.D. Chase certifying Validity of Purchase, December 10, 1862; 22317 (Folder 1)
  - Document signed by G.C. Dugan certifying Validity of Purchases, December 15, 1862; 22316 (Folder 1)
  - Letter from H.S. Woodward to Charles B. Johnson, December 23, 1862; 22315 (Folder 1)
  - Document signed by Samuel Hillbrauner certifying Validity of Purchases, December 29, 1862; 22314 (Folder 1)
  - Document signed by L.B. Barton certifying Validity of Purchases, January 1, 1862; 22313 (Folder 1)
- Series II: 1863-1865, 22303
  - Letter from unknown (Major G?) to Charles B. Johnson, January 26, 1863; 22311 (Folder 1)
  - Letter from G. Cawfield to Charles B. Johnson, January 29, 1863; 22310 (Folder 1)
  - Note from Captain Fraley to Charles B. Johnson Re: Supplies (with envelope), February 7, 1863; 22309 (Folder 1)
  - Note from G. Cawfield to Charles B. Johnson, February 26, 1863; 22308 (Folder 1)
  - List of items used by Charles B. Johnson during the 4th quarter, 1862, and 1st quarter, 1863, 1862-1863; 22307 (Folder 1)
  - Abstract of items purchased in Sherman, Texas, signed by Charles B. Johnson, March 31, 1863; 22306 (Folder 1)
  - Note from L.B. Pearson to Charles B. Johnson, June 5, 1863; 22305 (Folder 1)
  - Bill from United States Indian Department to Johnson and Grimes for Supplies, ca. June 1865; 22304 (Folder 1)